<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>automation on Bas-Man's Musings</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/categories/automation/</link><description>Recent content in automation on Bas-Man's Musings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bas-man.github.io/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Send a notification through LINE with AppDaemon with Home Assistant</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/home-assistant-appdaemon-line-notification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/home-assistant-appdaemon-line-notification/</guid><description>The challenge Living in Japan we generally default to using LINE for our messaging needs. At the time of this writing there is no integration for LINE within Home Assistant. Currently I use PushOver for some of my Home Assistant notifications. I also use Zapier with email to trigger notifications to my family LINE group. You can see how I did this here and here.
I also track some Tile devices to know when family members are home.</description></item><item><title>Use launchd instead of crontab on your Mac</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/launchd-instead-of-cron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 16:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/launchd-instead-of-cron/</guid><description>As of Mac OS 10.4 crontab has been depreciated but not ended. So its a good idea to know how to use its replacement under Mac OS. Welcome to Launchd.
This will be a short guide on how to use launchd in a simple form to replace a crontab job. In my case I am automating the backup of my Plex server. You can see my previous article here
Launchd has a lot of other features.</description></item><item><title>Delay Services launch until external drive mount is complete</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 14:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</guid><description>The Challenge How to give Drobo time to mount before processes that need access to it begin and hence block it&amp;rsquo;s mounting by having the mount point in use.
Solution AppleScript
Why was this an issue for me. Well I have a Drobo drive which is over 75% full. As a result it can take a while to mount and be detected by my old Mac Mini. This would mean that processes that use files from the Drobo would start before it was mounted.</description></item></channel></rss>