<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>automation on Bas-Man's Musings</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/categories/automation/</link><description>Recent content in automation on Bas-Man's Musings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 14:50:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bas-man.github.io/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Auto generate a static website after a remote push to the server.</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/cheatsheets/git/snippets/post-receive-hook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/cheatsheets/git/snippets/post-receive-hook/</guid><description>#!/bin/bash DOMAIN=[domain-name] GIT_REPO=/var/repos/[repo-name].repo.git WORKING_DIRECTORY=/tmp/$DOMAIN PUBLIC_WWW=/var/www/$DOMAIN BACKUP_WWW=/tmp/$DOMAIN-backup set -e rm -rf $WORKING_DIRECTORY rsync -aqz $PUBLIC_WWW/ $BACKUP_WWW trap &amp;#34;echo &amp;#39;A problem occurred. Reverting to backup.&amp;#39;; rsync -aqz --del $BACKUP_WWW/ $PUBLIC_WWW; r m -rf $WORKING_DIRECTORY&amp;#34; EXIT git clone $GIT_REPO $WORKING_DIRECTORY git clone https://github.com/[them] $WORKING_DIRECTORY/themes/beautifulhugo # The following section should be changed to use rsync so that it nicely updates # the directory instead of making it blank. rm -rf $PUBLIC_WWW/* hugo -s $WORKING_DIRECTORY -d $PUBLIC_WWW -b &amp;#34;http://${DOMAIN}&amp;#34; rm -rf $WORKING_DIRECTORY</description></item><item><title>Push to GitHub Triggers Push to Remote</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/git/push-to-github-triggers-push-to-remote/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 14:50:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/git/push-to-github-triggers-push-to-remote/</guid><description>Hi,
Today I would like to go over how I changed things up a bit and am now able to push my site updates to GitHub, which then pushes the updates to the live production server. This should allow me to add checks within GitHub to ensure my site it updated only if everything is correct. Though I won&amp;rsquo;t go into that here today. I will be focusing on the GitHub Action.</description></item><item><title>Auto Update Site from a Git Push</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/git/auto-update-site-from-git-push/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 14:40:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/git/auto-update-site-from-git-push/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a little while now I have been thinking about moving my personal blog to a self-hosted service. One of the options I have been considering is &lt;a href="https://www.linode.com">Linode&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of this idea. I wanted to see how I might be able to automate some of the processes. This is just a write up on one of my ideas so far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Send a notification through LINE with AppDaemon with Home Assistant</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/home-assistant-appdaemon-line-notification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/home-assistant-appdaemon-line-notification/</guid><description>The challenge Living in Japan we generally default to using LINE for our messaging needs. At the time of this writing there is no integration for LINE within Home Assistant. Currently I use PushOver for some of my Home Assistant notifications. I also use Zapier with email to trigger notifications to my family LINE group. You can see how I did this here and here.
I also track some Tile devices to know when family members are home.</description></item><item><title>Use launchd instead of crontab on your Mac</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/launchd-instead-of-cron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 16:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/launchd-instead-of-cron/</guid><description>As of Mac OS 10.4 crontab has been depreciated but not ended. So its a good idea to know how to use its replacement under Mac OS. Welcome to Launchd.
This will be a short guide on how to use launchd in a simple form to replace a crontab job. In my case I am automating the backup of my Plex server. You can see my previous article here
Launchd has a lot of other features.</description></item><item><title>Delay Services launch until external drive mount is complete</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 14:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</guid><description>The Challenge How to give Drobo time to mount before processes that need access to it begin and hence block it&amp;rsquo;s mounting by having the mount point in use.
Solution AppleScript
Why was this an issue for me. Well I have a Drobo drive which is over 75% full. As a result it can take a while to mount and be detected by my old Mac Mini. This would mean that processes that use files from the Drobo would start before it was mounted.</description></item></channel></rss>