<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>applescript on Bas-Man's Musings</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/categories/applescript/</link><description>Recent content in applescript on Bas-Man's Musings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 14:30:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bas-man.github.io/categories/applescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Delay Services launch until external drive mount is complete</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 14:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="the-challenge">The Challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How to give Drobo time to mount before processes that need access to it begin and hence block it's mounting by having the mount point in use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="solution">Solution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>AppleScript&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why was this an issue for me. Well I have a Drobo drive which is over 75% full.
As a result it can take a while to mount and be detected by my old Mac Mini. This would mean that processes that use files from the Drobo would start before it was mounted. And a mount point is use can not be mounted.&lt;/p>
&lt;script type="application/javascript" src="https://gist.github.com/Bas-Man/1abb5dafe36f0f06f727b00a214e855e.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;p>So let's break this down a little.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>line 1 sets a boolean that is false until &amp;quot;Finder&amp;quot; indicates that &amp;quot;Drobo&amp;quot; is seen. Drobo is the name that I have given to my Drobo drive, yes not very original.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lines 2 through to 9 wait for the Drobo to be mounted. Checking every 30 seconds. Once it's been found. The loop condition ends.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lines 12 to 14 then tell each application in turn to launch.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Open Apple's Script Editor and export as an Application.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open your &amp;quot;Users and Groups&amp;quot; manager.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select your user account and add the application to your &amp;quot;Login Items&amp;quot;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove any applications that you have added to the script from the &amp;quot;Login Items&amp;quot; if they are already present. You should be ok to go next time you reboot your machine.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>