<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Bas-Man's Ponderings</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Bas-Man's Ponderings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 23:00:39 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bas-man.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project: Self Hosted Zapier Alternative</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/self-hosted-zapier-alternative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 23:00:39 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/self-hosted-zapier-alternative/</guid><description>I am currently in the process of working out how I might replace some of my Zapier services. Why would I want to do this?
I use the free tier. (The process only runs once every 15 minutes. It used to be once every 5 mins.) Which means it has become a bit slow in sending the notifications. I want to learn how to use Docker Once I get a bit further along I will hopefully publish the python code to GitHub and document some of the issues and successes as I move along.</description></item><item><title>Send a notification through LINE with AppDaemon with Home Assistant</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/home-assistant-adddaemon-line-notification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/home-assistant-adddaemon-line-notification/</guid><description>The challenge Living in Japan we generally default to using LINE for our messaging needs. At the time of this writing there is no integration for LINE within Home Assistant. Currently I use PushOver for some of my Home Assistant notifications. I also use Zapier with email to trigger notifications to my family LINE group. You can see how I did this here and here.
I also track some Tile devices to know when family members are home.</description></item><item><title>Detect the OS Perl Code is Running Under</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/detect-os-perl-code-running-under/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 13:19:33 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/detect-os-perl-code-running-under/</guid><description>I was looking into updating a couple of my perl modules because rt.cpan.org is being sunset early in 2021. As part of this I thought it was time to stop cpan testers from testing my module under Windows since it is currently not really supported.
I was not sure how to go about doing this, so I reached out the good people in the &amp;ldquo;Perl Programmers&amp;rdquo; group on FaceBook. I got some great links and suggestions.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Stretch to Buster Missing Steps</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/raspberry-stretch-to-buster-missing-steps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 13:00:30 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/raspberry-stretch-to-buster-missing-steps/</guid><description>I recently went through the process of upgrading my raspberry Pis from Stretch to Buster. I had previously done this moving from Jessie.
Whilst I had no real issues with task following the guides that I found. I did discover one thing that concerned me, and was missing from the guides.
After upgrading to Buster, my /boot had less than 200kb of free storage.
I did some reading and found that Buster seems to need a lot more space in /boot than for previous releases.</description></item><item><title>Presence Detection with BLE using monitor.sh &amp; Home Assistant</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/ble-presence-detection-home-assistant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 10:35:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/ble-presence-detection-home-assistant/</guid><description>I have been running Home Assistant for a while. Things are going well. But I have had some issues with presence detection using the standard device_tracker component. Though I live in a small place, being in Tokyo, Home Assistant sometimes stops detecting phones if they are in an area of the apartment a little away from the Home Assistant server. This I suspect is due to the position of the Raspberry Pi and the building material.</description></item><item><title>Use launchd instead of crontab on your Mac</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/launchd-instead-of-cron/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 16:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/launchd-instead-of-cron/</guid><description>As of Mac OS 10.4 crontab has been depreciated but not ended. So its a good idea to know how to use its replacement under Mac OS. Welcome to Launchd.
This will be a short guide on how to use launchd in a simple form to replace a crontab job. In my case I am automating the backup of my Plex server. You can see my previous article here
Launchd has a lot of other features.</description></item><item><title>Publish your next Hugo blog post automatically using Github Actions</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/hugo-auto-publish/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/hugo-auto-publish/</guid><description>The Challenge I wanted to be able to publish a new post that has already been written at a future date, without needing to manually publish the article.
The Solution Github Actions.
I already push updates to my site using github actions. So I thought why not have articles published in the future after they are written.
A little background. I do all my edits in a private GitHub repo. When I push to master in this repo.</description></item><item><title>Private Hugo Repo to Public on Github</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/hugo-private-to-public-github/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 16:51:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/hugo-private-to-public-github/</guid><description>I was researching ways of moving to Hugo for my site generator. I looked at a few options and as part of this I came a cross a workflow in github that allows me to store my site in a private repo and then publish the site to a public repo without too much fuss.
You can find the action here
I use the basic example config with minor changes to match my GitHub details.</description></item><item><title>CI on Github for Python</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/github-python-action/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/github-python-action/</guid><description>So I finally thought it was time to start doing some continuous intergration testing as well as testing with multiple versions of Python.
I had been looking at using things such as CircleCI or Travis-ci. But I finally decided I would try to use Github&amp;rsquo;s workflow actions.
I did some searching and found some guides. As part of that I evenutally came a cross this link on Github&amp;rsquo;s own docs.</description></item><item><title>Add a cookie warning notice to a Hugo powered site</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/add-cookie-warning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/add-cookie-warning/</guid><description>The Challenge How to add a cookie warning notice to a Hugo powered website. But also avoid using a third party service.
The Solution Build your own. Well, find someone who built one and shared it on youtube and github.
Disclaimer: This does not constitute any form of legal advice. Use at your own risk.
Of course if anyone has a better, more complete solution. I would really like hear from you.</description></item><item><title>Back up your Plex Media Server on Mac OS</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/plex-macos-backup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/plex-macos-backup/</guid><description>The Challenge How to automate the backing up of my Plex Media Server
Solution A Bash Script
I wanted to automate this process. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t, it probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get done.
This script was adapted from another GitHub Gist that I found here.
You will probably need to modify the following variables.
plexDatabase plexPlistFile backupDirectory Pay attention to lines 17 ~ 21. These refer to the possibility that your script may not complete if your machine can go to sleep.</description></item><item><title>Delay Services launch until external drive mount is complete</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 14:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/startup-apple-script/</guid><description>The Challenge How to give Drobo time to mount before processes that need access to it begin and hence block it&amp;rsquo;s mounting by having the mount point in use.
Solution AppleScript
Why was this an issue for me. Well I have a Drobo drive which is over 75% full. As a result it can take a while to mount and be detected by my old Mac Mini. This would mean that processes that use files from the Drobo would start before it was mounted.</description></item><item><title>Site Launch</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/site-launched/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/site-launched/</guid><description>Well. Finally got around to putting this site together. Actually this is attempt number two.
I will try to post some of my small personal projects and thoughts here. I will also probably create a cheat sheet for myself.
Anyway, I shall see how it goes.</description></item></channel></rss>