<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>site on Bas-Man's Musings</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/tags/site/</link><description>Recent content in site on Bas-Man's Musings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 16:51:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bas-man.github.io/tags/site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Private Hugo Repo to Public on Github</title><link>https://bas-man.github.io/post/hugo-private-to-public-github/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 16:51:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://bas-man.github.io/post/hugo-private-to-public-github/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I was researching ways of moving to &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> for my site generator. I looked at a few options and as part of this I came a cross a workflow in github that allows me to store my site in a private repo and then publish the site to a public repo without too much fuss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the action &lt;a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/deploy-hugo-to-remote">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I use the basic example config with minor changes to match my GitHub details.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-basic-setup-is-as-follows">The basic setup is as follows&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create a private repo. This can be anything except site name used in step 2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a public repo named &lt;code>username.github.io&lt;/code> where username is your actual GitHub username.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="my-workflow">My workflow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Basically I edit my content locally in seperate branch from master. When I am finished and want to publish my content. I merge my changes in to the master branch. I then push my commits to my private repo. This in turn triggers the workflow. The workflow then builds the site in a virtual machine provided by github. It then clears out the public hosting repo and copies over the new contents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things to note:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You will need to configure a &lt;code>Personal Access Token&lt;/code>.
The workflow I use has a simple guide on this.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>